labroots.com 2019-08-16

# Privacy Policy | LabRoots

### Published May 21, 2018

This policy describes the ways LabRoots collects, stores, uses and protects your personal information. This Privacy Policy is a part of the LabRoots Authorized User Agreement (the "User Agreement"), and you accepted this policy when you registered for access to LabRoots website (the "Site") and agreed to the terms and conditions of the User Agreement. LabRoots may amend this policy from time to time by posting a revised version on the Site, and without giving you notice, so please check this policy each time you visit the Site and note the date of publication.

**Registration:  **In order to become a LabRoots user, you must first create an account on this Site. To create an account, you are required to provide the following information: name, email address, country, ZIP/postal code, your primary scientific discipline, a brief summary of your professional background (current occupation and networking objectives), and you must choose a password.

**Profile Information:  **Once a user, you may provide additional information in the Profile section describing your skills, professional experiences, and expanding on your networking objectives. Providing additional information beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional, and enables you to better identify yourself and find opportunities on the Site.

**Invite Others:  **If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. LabRoots stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. Your friend may contact us at [privacy@labroots.com](mailto:%20privacy@labroots.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

You may also choose to manually enter or upload data about your contacts into your private "My Contacts" section of the Site. All information entered in your "My Contacts" section can only be viewed by you and is not searchable by other Site users without your permission. All information that you enter or upload about your contacts will be covered by the same terms of this privacy policy that cover your own personally identifiable information.

**Cookies & Log Files: **Like most websites, this Site uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. A cookie is a tiny data file that resides on your computer and allows us to recognize you as a user when you return to the Site using the same computer and web browser. Like the information you enter at registration or in your Profile, cookie and log file data is used to customize your experience on the Site. However, if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to use our Site.

One type of cookie, known as a "persistent" cookie, is set when you log in to your LabRoots account. The next time you visit the Site, the persistent cookie will allow us to recognize you as an existing user so you will not need to re-enter your password before using the Site. In order to access or change any of your private information (like a credit card number), you must log in securely by re-entering your password even if your computer contains your persistent cookie. If you log out of the Site, you will need to re-enter your password the next time you visit the Site in order to log in to your account. Another type of cookie, called a "session" cookie, is used to identify a particular visit to the Site. Session cookies expire after a short time or when you close your web browser.

Due to Internet communications standards, when you visit our Site, we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave. We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, as well as the name of your Internet service provider. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve our Site and its operation. The link between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is never shared with third-parties without your permission or except in accordance with applicable law.

**Information Use:** LabRoots is an online service dedicated to helping scientific professionals more effectively connect with one another. The personally identifiable information you choose to provide on this Site for your profile is used to help you describe yourself to other users. Other information that does not personally identify you as an individual is collected through data mining technology from the Site in order to create a semantic comparison for relevant content (such as, by way of example, patterns of Site usage) and is exclusively owned by LabRoots. This information can be used by LabRoots in such manner as LabRoots, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate, including advertising targeted to generic users with profiles of similar content and/or similar patterns of Site usage.

**LabRoots Communications:  **LabRoots will communicate with you through email and notices posted on the website. These include a series of welcome emails, event reminders, newsletters, sponsored emails and update emails which help inform users about various website features and releases. Please be aware that you will continue to receive certain emails from LabRoots relating to the proper functioning of your account.

**LabRoots works with MailChimp**  
LabRoots sends all email communication through a viable third party named MailChimp. More than 12 million people and businesses around the world use MailChimp. MailChimp features and integrations allow their clients to send marketing emails, automated messages, and targeted campaigns. And MailChimp detailed reports help their clients keep improving over time. MailChimp has been around since 2001. The company started as a side project funded by various web-development jobs. Now we’re the world’s leading email marketing platform, and MailChimp sends more than a billion emails a day. 

**LabRoots E-Newsletters**  
During registration for LabRoots, the user goes through a step to Opt-In for LabRoots E-Newsletters by clicking all the newsletter categories the user would like to receive. If the user wishes to no longer receive LabRoots E-Newsletters that can do one of two things: 1) The user can simply click on the Unsubscribe link located at the bottom of the E-Newsletter. All LabRoots E-Newsletter must always have the Unsubscribe link option at the bottom of the E-Newsletter. 2) The user can email LabRoots at [ privacy@labroots.com](mailto:%20privacy@labroots.com?subject=Email%20Privacy) or call us at +1-714-463-4673 to let us know, and we will remove you immediately. 

**Emails from LabRoots Sponsors and Partners**  
During registration for a LabRoots virtual event or webinar, the user is asked a question if they would like to receive emails from the Sponsors of that specific event/webinar. The answer does not default to Yes or No, the user has to choose to receive communication from the sponsor or not. If the user does choose yes or opt-in to receive email communication from the sponsor the user can always opt out or unsubscribe at any time. The user has two options to do so: 1) All sponsor-related emails provide an easy and free means by which the user can opt-out of future sponsor-related emails, and if the user opts out the user request is adhered to in all future email marketing. The user can simply click on the Unsubscribe link located at the bottom of the sponsor's email. 2) The user can email LabRoots at [ privacy@labroots.com](mailto:%20privacy@labroots.com?subject=Email%20Privacy) or call us at +1-714-463-4673 to let us know, and we will contact the sponsor immediately. 

**Sponsors**

 By agreeing to be contacted by our sponsors you agree to be contacted by any of the following sponsors (this list is subject to change without notice and consent applies to all additions).

Thermo Fisher Scientific, Qiagen, Sony, Abbott Diagnostics, Millipore Sigma, Abcam, Illumina, Agilent, Eppendorf, Bruker, Diagnostica Stago, AMP (Assoc. for Mol. Patholgy), Leica, Roche, Direct Effect Media, Society for Neuroscience (SFN), Nanostring, PerkinElmer, IonPath, Twist Bioscience, Cell Signaling Technology, Oxford Nanoimaging, DNA Nexus, LabCyte, Essen Bioscience, Canon, Synthego, Qlucore, Techlab, Atlas Antibodies, Proteintech, ProteinSimple, Molecular Devices, Gentegra, Bio-Techne, Bio-Rad, Unchained Labs, Gilson, LR Store, Baker Ruskin, BD Genomics, Definiens, 10X Genomics, Luminex, Cisbio, LGC, Diasorin, ABSA, Pall Life Sciences, Cepheid, DNA Nexus, Beckman Coulter, EliTech, Vium, MBL, Oxford Genetics, Prometic Bioseparations, Gold Standard Diagnostics, Reichert, Nanotemper Technologies, Percepta Associates, Pacific Biosystems, Proton Onsite, Microbiome Insights, Genscript, SCIEX, Promega, Cloudlims, Charles River Labs, Enzo, Helmer, Daigger Scientific, MaxCyte, Rocky Mountain Diagnostics, QSI, BellBrook Labs, Terumo, Crown Bioscience, Virtual Chemistry, Andor, SAI Infusion Technologies, Strand Life Sciences, GE Life Sciences, Fluidigm, Shimadzu, MissionBio, M3, Stemcell Technologies, Miltenyi, ICARE, Envigo

**Email Opt-In Laws and Legislation**  
LabRoots adheres to the following legal requirements for sending out email marketing messages globally:  
**1)  **United States: "CAN-SPAM Act" The Controlling the Assault of Non-Solicited Pornography and Marketing Act of 2003. The CAN-SPAM Act covers commercial email messages with the primary purpose of advertisement or promotion of a commercial product or service. Don't use false or misleading header information. Don't use deceptive subject lines. Tell recipients where your location. Tell recipients how to opt out of emails. Honor opt-out requests promptly.  
**2)** Europe: "Directive on privacy and electronic communications" Directive 2002/58/EC (specifies minimum legislation for member states). Directive 2003/58/EC (amending Council Directive 68/151/EEC). The Directive on privacy and electronic communications covers all direct email marketing messages, including charitable and political messages. Don't send direct marketing without permission. Don't conceal the sender's identity. Provide a valid address for the user to opt-out. Provide proof of sign up if asked.  
**3)** Canada: "CASL - Canada's Anti-Spam Legislation." Only send to permission-based email addresses. Identify your name and business. Provide proof of sign up if asked.  
**4)** Australia: "Spam Act 2003". Don't send unsolicited emails. You must have permission to send emails. Include functional unsubscribe options in all email communication. Don't use address-harvesting software in any capacity.  
**5)** Similar laws exist in other countries. They all request you use an opt-in form, keep your list clean and avoid penalties. Emailing through an email service such as MailChimp, which will also keep your email in compliance with email laws around the world. LabRoots does this!

**GDPR Regulations and Compliance**

The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) replaces the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and was designed to harmonize data privacy laws across Europe, to protect and empower all EU citizens data privacy and to reshape the way organizations across the region approach data privacy. The key articles of the GDPR, as well as information on its business impact, can be found throughout this site: https://www.eugdpr.org/ 

**(1) Information We Collect**

Site: We may collect personally identifiable information about you, such as your email address, full name, mailing address, phone number, phone number type, current job title, current institution, current institution type, spoken language, timezone, and areas of interest when you register for an account. Additional personally identifiable information can be provided by you after an account has been created, such as educational history, work experience history, social media accounts, and gender. We also use Google Analytics to capture your movement and decisions throughout our website.

**(2) How We Use Your Information**

We use the information that we collect to operate and maintain our Site, send you marketing communications, provide you with relevant content, respond to your questions and concerns.

**(3) How We Share Your Information**

(a) Personally Identifiable Information: LabRoots will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others without your express consent. We may store personal information in locations outside of the direct control of LabRoots (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). Any personally identifiable information that you elect to make publicly available on our Site, such as posting comments on any of our pages, will be available to others. If you remove information that you have made public on Our Service, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of our Site, or if other users have copied and saved that information. 

(b) Non-Personally Identifiable Information: We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain LabRoots Services.

**(4) Storage and Processing**

Your information collected through our Site may be stored and processed in the United States, Europe, or any other country in which LabRoots or its affiliates or service providers maintain facilities.

**(5) How We Protect Your Information**

LabRoots is concerned with protecting your privacy and data, but we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to LabRoots or guarantee that your information on our Site may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of any of our industry standard physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. When you enter sensitive information (such as login credentials) on our registration forms or within your profile, we encrypt that information using Transport Layer Security (TLS). No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about the security on our Site, you can contact us at privacy@labroots.com

**(6) Access, Correction, Deletion**

We respect your privacy right and provide you with reasonable access to the Personal Data that you may have provided through your use of the Site. If you wish to access or amend any other Personal Data we hold about you or to request that we delete any information about you that we have obtained, you may contact us at https://www.labroots.com/user-data-request. At your request, we will have any reference to you deleted or blocked in our database

You may update, correct, or request to delete your Account information and preferences at any time by accessing your Account Settings page on our Site. Please note, while any changes you make will be reflected in active user databases instantly, or within a reasonable period of time. We may retain all information you submit for backups, archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, analytics, satisfaction of legal obligations, or where we otherwise reasonably believe that we have a legitimate reason to do so.

You may decline to share certain Personal Data with us, in which case we may not be able to provide you some of the features and functionality of the Service.

At any time, you may object to the processing of your Personal Data, on legitimate grounds, except if otherwise permitted by applicable law.  

**Customized Content:  **Information you provide at registration or in your Profile section is also used to customize your experience on the Site. For example, based on the discipline you enter in your Profile, you will receive targeted news, publications, event notices, job postings, and advertisements that may be of particular interest to you.

**Sharing Information With Third Parties:  **LabRoots takes the privacy of our users very seriously. We will never sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to any third parties for marketing purposes. We will only share your personally identifiable with third parties to carry out your instructions and to provide specific services. For instance, we use a credit card processing company to bill users for purchases made on the Site. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services and are bound by strict confidentiality agreements that limit their use of such information. LabRoots offers a "public profile" feature that allows users to publish portions of their Profile, including "name," but not "email address" to the public Internet. Users may opt-out of this feature. However, we do not warrant how third-party search engines will update their cache.

We may provide aggregated data about Site usage to third-parties for such purposes as we deem appropriate, in our sole discretion. We may segment our users by role (i.e., particle physicist, research assistant), a field of science, geographic location, and company/university affiliation. If you would like to be excluded from the aggregated data we use to generate research or reports about our users' activities on the Site, please send a request to privacy@labroots.com.

**Partnering with Other Companies to Offer Combined Services:** LabRoots may partner with other online services to offer you a variety of services. Whenever we offer such combined services, it will be your choice to make use of such services or not. In these cases, your personally identifiable information will only be passed from LabRoots to the partner if you choose to use the combined service.

**Communications Between Users:** Many emails you initiate through the Site (for example, an invitation sent to a non-user), will list your email address and name in the header of the message. Emails you initiate may also provide aggregate information about your network (for instance, how many people are in your network), but will never list the people to whom you're directly connected. Other communications that you initiate through the Site (for example, a request for contact), will list your name as the initiator but will not include your personal contact information. Your contact information will only be shared with another user if both of you have indicated that you would like to establish contact with each other.

If you use a bulletin board, a discussion forum ("Q & A forum") or blog on this Website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Legal Disclaimer:** It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information in accordance with applicable laws. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, other legal process served on LabRoots, or to exercise our legal rights or to defend against legal claims.

**Accessing and Changing Your Account Information:** You can review the personal information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information, or to the settings for your LabRoots account, at any time by logging in to your account on the Site and editing the information on your Profile page. You can also close your account through the Site. If you close your Labroots account, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable data. We may retain certain data contributed by you if it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally-identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. All retained data will continue to be subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy. To request that we close your account and remove your information from the Site, please send your request to privacy@labroots.com. Please send your request using an email account that you have registered with LabRoots under your name. You will receive a response to requests sent to privacy@labroots.com within three business days after we receive your request.

**Security:  **In order to secure your personal information, access to your data on the Site is password-protected.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy:** If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the homepage and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email or by means of a notice on our homepage.

**Questions or Comments:  **If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy, please email us at [privacy@labroots.com](mailto:%20privacy@labroots.com) or write to LabRoots, Inc., 18340 Yorba Linda Blvd., Suite 107 PMB 427, Yorba Linda, CA 92886.
